The Princess Sapphire
♪ Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano ♪
The dreams I see are my secret
♪ Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano ♪
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
♪ Akai manto hira hira ♪
A red cape fluttering
♪ Uma o tobasu oujo ♪
Galloping on a horse—the princess
♪ Sore ga atashi ♪
That’s me!
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Ribon no kishi wa ♪
The Princess Knight,
♪ Honto wa hontto wa ♪
Truly, truly,
♪ Atashi nano sa ♪
It’s really me!
Sixth Episode
The Little Goblin
On an island in the South,
in the Southern sea,
there is a little elf
who plays and wants to play!
On that island in the South,
in the blue Southern sea,
there is a cheeky elf
who knows how to use his magic!
Even if it's not very pretty,
this is my boat,
so please
don't laugh at it!
- It's not ugly! It's just funny!
- I like it!
How fun!
I feel like a sailor!
But what do I see?
I see something..
And what is this?
A seashell...
Let me out, please!
- I hear a voice...
- Let me out!
Help me!
Please, let me out!
Heavens, what a surprise!
Where is he? Where is he? Where is he?
It's costing me dearly to follow
Prince Sapphire on his vacation!
I can't do anything about it at all,
damn it!
It's an order
from Grand Duke Geralamon.
- Here comes that little angel!
- There is an elf inside here!
An elf in a seashell?!
Yes! They had locked me
in here!
Thank you for saving me
He says he comes
from a distant southern island..
...and that he was
dragged all the way here,
always locked inside his shell.
What is your father's name,
little elf?
His name is Genie.
Did you say "Genie"? But isn't he
the spirit of the magic lamp,
the one from the fairy tales
of "One Thousand and One Nights"?
Yes, he used to be in the lamp,
but now he is old...
...and prefers to live on
an island in the South Seas.
Ah, the genie of the magic
lamp! Ah, interesting news!
I heard that the magic
lamp granted every wish...
- Shut up!
- My father granted wishes.
...of whoever possessed the magic
lamp, but he stopped doing so!
Since you saved me, I will
have your wishes granted.
In return, I ask you only one thing.
If I get you what you want do
you promise to take me back home?
I mean, I want to say,
on the South Seas island!
My father hasn't seen me in a long
time and he must be worried!
I heard a noise!
- That's..! Do you believe it, Choppy?
- I do! And you, Sapphire?
I think he told
a pack of lies!
- I think he's a liar!
- NO! What I told you is true..
...and I'll prove it to you
if you take me home!
I can't bring myself to believe
his words!
Sapphire, I feel sorry for that poor guy
It's none of my business!
You keep him!
Sapphire, wait!
The genie of the magic lamp
grants every wish,
so if I can catch
that pixie..!
What are you doing, Baron Neelon?
Hello, Your Highness! I was just passing by!
Liar! That will teach you to lie!
Actually, I was on my way
to your castle!
Then hurry on over there!
- Of course, Your Highness!
- Wait for me, I'm coming with you!
This Sapphire
is really a fool.
I didn't like Sapphire.
He was truly heartless.
Don't worry, little elf
I will take you to your home,
on that island in the South Seas.
Wait, little one! Don't go
out to sea! Give me that elf!
I wouldn't even think of it!
So much the worse for you! Now I...
Hey!
How come you came back?
It's dangerous for little ones
to play with boats, and I...
Choppy, come back to shore!
Choppy, do you hear me? Come back, I said!
You said you didn't believe
his words.
Stop! Don't be foolish! You won't
manage to reach the island!
How stubborn!
Listen to me, Choppy!
In the sea there are sharks
...that eat men and
whales and other monstrous animals!
Now you'll see!
Do you want to leave me alone?
Listen, Choppy,
I would like to go home.
I will take you there! For now you can
stay in my hat.
Choppy is really hospitable!
I don't want to go back!
Let me go!
The shark!
Watch out, Choppy! Run!
Help!
Here!
Try to catch me!
Run, Choppy!
I'll try to help you!
There it is!
Oh my, there are so many
of them! It's a whole pack!
Hooray, I'm saved!
Maybe I made it!
I wonder if this is the island of
the South Seas..! Who knows?
Hey, but that
looks like a whale to me!
Choppy, that's not
an island! It's a whale!
A whale?! I thought it
was a Southern island!
Help!
Here! Take the anchor, Choppy!
I missed it!
Don't go down, Choppy!
Too late!
Now it's going too fast!
I should run for it, but I
can't abandon Choppy!
An island!
It's going to crash into the island!
It won't even stop
on dry land!
I have to stop it!
I've got it!
What's down there? A ship!
Hey, the ship!
What a crash!
But it's not a dinosaur,
it's a rock!
Help! Help, Sapphire!
I can't swim!
- Hold onto my hand!
- I can't reach!
Now I can touch the bottom.
How come? I can touch too.
What could it be, Sapphire?
Can you explain this mystery?
- Look!
- What do you think it is?
I don't know.
It's a flying manta ray, Choppy!
Hold on tight! Here's another one!
Sapphire!
Where could I be? I'm lost
in the middle of the ocean!
An island!
It's the South Seas island!
Hooray, I've arrived!
It's the island! Finally!
But where is Sapphire?
I've got it! I'll light a fire
to let her know where I am!
I hope she sees the smoke
What is it? Ah, it's you
who spoke! What are you?
- Let me go!
- A dinosaur!
Ah, is that so? Come on!
- So many monsters!
- What's happening? Why did you call?
Let's teach them a lesson!
Better run for it!
How strange..!
On this island, trees and
animals are smaller than normal!
Maybe this
is the elf's island!
Come here, see if you
recognize the island!
I'm scared, Choppy! I'm scared!
This is not my island!
This is a very strange place!
- Get off our island!
- Get lost!
Did you see how I chased him away?
This bird
is as small as a fly.
Help! Help!
A swarm of them is coming!
Damn, they don't intend
to stop! Help! Help!
Yes, I definitely want to leave
this place! But how do I do it?
Here's the solution!
This small-scale whirlwind
will carry me away!
How wonderful! It feels
like I'm on a carousel!
I see a wisp of smoke!
Maybe there's someone on
this island! Maybe Choppy is here!
Choppy, where are you? Choppy!
Look, look...! They look like
the footprints of Choppy's shoes!
Choppy, it's me: Sapphire!
Where are you, Choppy?
Strange! His footprints
end on this rocky ledge!
Could it be...
Where am I? Where have we
ended up? A giant footprint!
But then... There are giants!
- Giants?!
- Don't be afraid, little elf!
I will protect you.
Perhaps, from the island
of dwarfs, that whirlwind...
...has brought us to the island
of giants. You will stay in a shell.
I don't want to stay here!
- Everything is so huge!
- Let me out, I said!
Please, stay quiet or
the giants will hear you!
Oh, goodness! What could it be?
Please, Mrs. Frog, don't eat me!
Help! It's chasing me! Help!
I am indigestible, Mrs. Frog!
Where can I hide? Oh, there!
No, don't shake too much, please!
There are so many of them!
- I want to get out!
- Quiet, or the giant will hear you!
We must leave immediately!
More frogs?!
Welcome, little boy!
And yet, they don't seem bad.
I am the chief
and I welcome you!
- No, I am the chief!
- Don't listen to him! I'm in charge!
I gather that you want
something from me.
Yes! Please! Help us!
How can I help you if I don't
know the danger that threatens you?
That man wants to eat us!
Blast it!
Good heavens! These
frogs are poisonous!
I see Choppy's footprints.
He must be on this island!
Choppy! It's me! It's Sapphire!
Sapphire! The
giant has taken her!
Let's see... Where is she?
Now I can escape!
He's so huge! I will never manage
to defeat him by normal means!
Oh, there he is!
I can't go any further!
Sapphire, get out of there
or the giant will kill you!
Damn! He's going to
make the mountain collapse!
Here is what I'll do! I must
go to the frogs I met earlier.
Only they can help us!
May I ask a question?
I will help you against the giant if
you tell me where you got the poison!
We get it from
the root of a plant!
Do you have any more of those roots?
- Yes, of course!
- Absolutely!
Now listen to me carefully!
You will put some poison in
your mouth and spit it at the giant!
- In our mouths?
- Of course! You will spit it at him!
Alright, we understand!
He managed
to widen the crack!
I don't want to die in a place
like this! I must do something!
Green and sparkling,
we are the frogs!
Here we are, leaping,
all together we arrive!
Stop now!
We're almost there!
I will at least try
to cut off his finger!
Are you ready to spit the poison?
Spit!
He's hit!
Why is the giant
leaving?
What do I see! That's Choppy!
- Sapphire!
- Choppy!
I am so glad
that you are safe!
Thank the frogs! They were the
ones who chased the giant away!
You know, by now I had lost
all hope of finding you alive.
I'm deeply moved!
Look! The giant is washing himself,
so he can wash off the poison!
I think he intends to
climb all the way up here.
I will cut the ivy, to stop
him from climbing up!
- Let me out! It's important!
- We are still in danger!
We could escape quickly
and you're fine where you are!
I'm missing one, Sapphire! Only one!
I have to get out!
I made it, finally!
This is my island
and that is my father!
Really? Then how do you explain
that he has a horn and you don't?
He has it because we grow a horn
when we get angry!
You grew one too!
Then you are his son!
Please, don't hurt him!
What are you doing? Stop!
That giant is my father!
What?! Really?!
Dad! Dad! It's me!
I'm your son!
Little Elf! Is it really you?
- Yes, it's me!
- My dear son!
I'll catch you! There!
- My little elf!
- Dear dad, I missed you so much!
I couldn't wait to see you again!
The last section is breaking!
It's falling!
I'm happy to see you again
Me too, dad!
These two guys are my friends!
They are so kind!
They brought me back here to you!
I am so grateful to you! I was so worried
and anxious about my little one!
So he is the genie
of the magic lamp!
Promise me you will never go
to the beach to play alone again!
I promise, Dad:
I won't ever leave you again!
I'm sorry you were so worried
about me all this time!
Out of gratitude,
I will grant your wishes.
Thank you,
there is no need to trouble yourself
- I'm sorry about the misunderstanding.
- I am too!
But I'd like to return
your kindness.
Then could you make it so
that Sapphire can be happy?
I prefer to earn it
on my own, happiness.
Dad could free you
from all your enemies.
I will manage to get rid of them
with my own strength.
Dad told me that a certain
Neelon chased you all the way here.
He must have wanted to set a trap for me!
Indeed, he certainly looked like it!
But don't worry!
Since he seemed bad,
I transformed him with
magic into a seagull!
Into a seagull?!
Have a safe trip, guys!
- Goodbye, Genie!
- Restore Neelon to his true form!
I really think this has
been a good lesson for him!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen ♪
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
♪ Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen ♪
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
♪ Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo ♪
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
♪ tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai ♪
Our bonded hearts will never part.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/translator/natalia-arlovskaya